Guide to Komunidad: Filipinos in the UAE AD.MC.016
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Komunidad: Filipinos in the UAE
2015-2016
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
Bacani, Xyza, Ms
AD.MC.016
1 Linear Feet
Arrangement
The collection was processed as it was received from the photographer.
Xyza Cruz Bacani
Xyza Cruz Bacani is a Filipina Street and Documentary Photographer who has been featured in New York Times Lens Blog, CNN and various International media publication not only for her excellence in photography but also for her inspirational story. Working as a domestic worker for almost a decade, she used photography to tell the stories of her fellow domestic workers and others who were victims of human rights violation. She is one of the Magnum Foundation Human Rights Fellow 2015,exhibited in South East Asia, won awards in photography and she was granted HR No. 1969 by the Philippines House of Representative. Xyza is one of BBC 100 Women 2015 and a Fujifilm Ambassador.
Komunidad: Filipinos in the UAE
There are around 400,000 Filipino migrants in the UAE. They form a significant part of the approximately 10 million Filipinos who work outside of the Philippines. These ten million constitute roughly 9 per cent of the population of the Philippines and their remittances make a major contribution to the country's economy. Xyza Bacani's documentary photography project focuses on the Overseas Filipino Workers (or OFWs) in the UAE where they are part of a truly global population. The project follows the daily lives of four Filipinos living in the country and provides a glimpse into their community.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection obtained directly from the creator, Xyza Cruz Bacani in 2016.
Taguig, Philippines; Philippines; Nueva Ecija, Philippines; Manila, Philippines; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; NYU Abu Dhabi; Digital Photographs; Immigration; Workers
- Judjet at an inspection, NYUAD, November 2015; cuid1401; 5657; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref1_m)
  Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Immigration; NYU Abu Dhabi; Digital Photographs; Individual Portraits; Men; Workers
- Portrait of Judjet inside the car park, November 2015; cuid1402; 5658; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref2_m)
  NYU Abu Dhabi; Immigration; Individual Portraits; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Digital Photographs; Men; Workers; Cars/Trucks; Transportation
- Judjet with the workers during an inspection, November 2015; 5659; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref3_m)
  Digital Photographs; NYU Abu Dhabi; Immigration; Men; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Workers
- Judjet at an inspection, NYUAD, November 2015; 5660; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref4_m)
  Digital Photographs; Men; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Immigration; NYU Abu Dhabi; Workers
- Judjet has lunch with Filipino colleagues, NYUAD, November 2015; 5661; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref5_m)
  Women; Men; Digital Photographs; Immigration; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; NYU Abu Dhabi; Food; Group Portraits; Workers
- Filipino migrant workers inside a mall in Abu Dhabi during their day off, November 2015; 5663; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref7_m)
  Women; Men; Restaurants/bars; Immigration; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Digital Photographs; NYU Abu Dhabi; Food
- Friday Church service in St. Joseph's Cathedral, Abu Dhabi, November 2015; 5724; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref10_m)
  Women; Immigration; Digital Photographs; Men; Churches; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Religious Sites
- Catholics line up to receive the holy communion, St. Joseph's Cathedral, Abu Dhabi, November 2015; 5725; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref11_m)
  Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Women; Men; Digital Photographs; Immigration; Churches; Religious Sites
- Judjet after the mass in St. Joseph's Cathedral, Abu Dhabi, November 2015; 5726; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref12_m)
  Digital Photographs; Immigration; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Girls; Women; Churches; Children; Men; Religious Sites
- Judjet's wall at home, Abu Dhabi, November 2015; 5727; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref13_m)
  Digital Photographs; Immigration; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Children; Men; Women
- Filipino migrant workers drink together after a busy day at work., November 2015; 5728; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref14_m)
  Women; Men; Drinks/Beverages; Digital Photographs; Immigration; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
- Amber and Jonathan, Dubai, November 2015; 5729; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref15_m)
  Immigration; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Children; Men; Girls; Digital Photographs
- Claire prepares breakfast, Dubai, November 2015; 5730; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref16_m)
  Food; Immigration; Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
- Typical Filipino food, November 2015; 5731; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref17_m)
  Immigration; Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Food
- Migrant workers buy fish in Deira, Dubai, November 2015; 5732; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref18_m)
  Men; Immigration; Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
- Claire eats dinner with her family in Dubai, November 2015; 5733; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref19_m)
  Immigration; Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Women; Girls; Children; Food
- Claire plays with her daughter Amber, who just arrived in Dubai., November 2015; 5734; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref20_m)
  Immigration; Women; Digital Photographs; Girls; Children; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
- Claire and Jonathan Onte inside their flat, Dubai, November 2015; 5735; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref21_m)
  Girls; Children; Immigration; Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Dubai, United Arab Emirates
- Portrait of Jonathan Onte, Dubai, November 2015; 5736; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref22_m)
  Immigration; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Digital Photographs; Men; Individual Portraits
- Amber watches cartoons on her phone. Dubai, November 2015; 5737; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref23_m)
  Digital Photographs; Immigration; Telephones; Children; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Individual Portraits; Girls
- Claire, Dubai, November 2015; 5738; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref24_m)
  Digital Photographs; Immigration; Individual Portraits; Dubai, United Arab Emirates; Women
- A basketball match, November 2015; 5739; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref25_m)
  NYU Abu Dhabi; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Sports; Immigration; Men; Digital Photographs
- Filipino migrants workers inside the Philippine Embassy, Abu Dhabi, November 2015; 5742; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref28_m)
  Digital Photographs; Men; Women; Immigration; Embassies; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates
- Inside the Philippine Embassy in Abu Dhabi, November 2015; 5743; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref29_m)
  Women; Immigration; Men; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; Embassies; Digital Photographs
- Consultation and activities are offered in the Embassy, Abu Dhabi, November 2015; 5744; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref30_m)
  Women; Immigration; Digital Photographs; Embassies; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates
- Mark's youngest son is playing inside their home in Manila, Philippines., December 2015; 5748; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref34_m)
  Immigration; Manila, Philippines; Digital Photographs; Men; Boys; Children
- Mark Anthony Enriquez and his family inside their home in Manila., December 2015; 5749; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref35_m)
  Manila, Philippines; Immigration; Digital Photographs; Women; Children; Men; Group Portraits; Furnishings; Boys; Girls; Toys; Facial Hair
- Christmas decorations displayed inside the Enriquez home in Manila, Philippines., December 2015; 5750; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref36_m)
  Manila, Philippines; Immigration; Digital Photographs; Christmas
- Catholic icons displayed inside the Enriquez home in Manila, Philippines, December 2015; 5751; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref37_m)
  Manila, Philippines; Immigration; Digital Photographs
- Portrait of Mark Enriquez in Manila, Philippines, December 2015; 5752; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref38_m)
  Digital Photographs; Immigration; Manila, Philippines; Men; Individual Portraits
- Mark's neighborhood in Manila, Philippines, December 2015; 5753; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref39_m)
  Immigration; Manila, Philippines; Digital Photographs; Men
- Filipino migrant workers leaving the country say goodbye to their families at the Manila airport., January 2016; 5764; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref50_m)
  Manila, Philippines; Digital Photographs; Immigration; Philippines; Men; Women
- View from Judjet's family home in Taguig, Philippines, December 2015; 5765; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref51_m)
  Taguig, Philippines; Digital Photographs; Immigration; Philippines
- Judjet in the bedroom, Taguig, Philippines, December 2015; 5766; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref52_m)
  Philippines; Men; Taguig, Philippines; Individual Portraits; Digital Photographs; Immigration
- Judjet with his mother as they watch Judget's daughter play inside their home in Taguig, Philippines, December 2015; 5767; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref53_m)
  Girls; Immigration; Digital Photographs; Women; Children; Philippines; Taguig, Philippines; Men
- Judjet's family home, Taguig, Philippines, December 2015; 5768; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref54_m)
  Digital Photographs; Taguig, Philippines; Immigration; Philippines
- Judjet spends time with his neighbors, Taguig, Philippines, December 2015; 5769; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref55_m)
  Children; Taguig, Philippines; Men; Girls; Digital Photographs; Immigration; Philippines
- Judjet's daughter playing, December 2015; 5770; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref56_m)
  Immigration; Taguig, Philippines; Digital Photographs; Philippines; Girls; Children
- Judjet with his phone. Mementos on the wall, December 2015; 5771; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref57_m)
  Immigration; Digital Photographs; Telephones; Philippines; Taguig, Philippines; Individual Portraits
- Judjet fixes the door while his mother prepares lunch in their family home. Philippines, December 2015; 5772; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref58_m)
  Digital Photographs; Immigration; Men; Philippines; Taguig, Philippines; Children; Women
- Judjet in the Philippines, December 2015; 5773; Bacani, Xyza, Ms (Object AD-MC-016_ref59_m)
  Girls; Digital Photographs; Taguig, Philippines; Children; Immigration; Philippines; Men